[
    {
        "question": "Which of the following preparation needs to be done before IPS flooring?",
        "options": [
            "Removal of debris",
            "Slurry application",
            "Button marking",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why it is important to fill gaps in shuttering?",
        "options": [
            "It allows air inside concrete",
            "It prevents leakage of slurry",
            "It makes concrete more strong",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "It prevents leakage of slurry"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the advantages of IPS flooring?",
        "options": [
            "Low cost",
            "Durable",
            "Easy maintenance",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following aggregate is best suitable for IPS flooring?",
        "options": [
            "20mm aggregate",
            "10 mm aggregate",
            "40mm aggregate",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "10 mm aggregate"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which among the following will lead to a more durable and higher strength concrete?",
        "options": [
            "High water-cement ratio",
            "Low water-cement ratio",
            "All of the above",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Low water-cement ratio"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which tool is used to transfer reference level?",
        "options": [
            "Plumb Bob",
            "Measuring Tape",
            "Line Dori",
            "Water Level"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Water Level"
    },
      {
        "question": "After placement of concrete, what plays important role in gaining the strength to concrete?",
        "options": [
            "Adequate concreting",
            "Removal of shuttering within an hour",
            "Removal of shuttering after one month",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Adequate concreting"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following material can be used as joint filler in tremix?",
        "options": [
            "Sand",
            "Water",
            "Asphalt",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Asphalt"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the advantage of Tremix flooring?",
        "options": [
            "High compressive strength",
            "Higher wear resistant",
            "Both",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Both"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which tool is used for compaction of concrete?",
        "options": [
            "Cutter",
            "Vibrator",
            "Hammer",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Vibrator"
    },
 {
        "question": "It is advisable to pour concrete from lower height, Why?",
        "options": [
            "It gives more strength",
            "It helps in less consumption of concrete",
            "It avoids segregation of aggregate",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "It avoids segregation of aggregate"
    },
    {
        "question": "What do you understand by 1:2:4?",
        "options": [
            "1-part sand, 2-part cement, 4-part aggregate",
            "1-part sand, 4-part cement, 2-part aggregate",
            "1-part cement, 2-part sand, 4-part aggregate",
            "1-part aggregate, 2-part cement, 4-part sand"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "1-part cement, 2-part sand, 4-part aggregate"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the importance of concrete cover for reinforcement?",
        "options": [
            "Protects rebar from corrosion",
            "Provide resistant against fire",
            "Both",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Both"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the factors which may affect concrete strength?",
        "options": [
            "Proper Vibration",
            "Water Cement Ratio",
            "Slump",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "Workability of concrete is tested by __________.",
        "options": [
            "Water content test",
            "Compression test",
            "Slump test",
            "Penetration test"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Slump test"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which tool is used for groove cutting in concrete?",
        "options": [
            "Groove cutter",
            "Vibrator",
            "Hammer",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Groove cutter"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following method is most suitable for curing of slab?",
        "options": [
            "Ponding",
            "Sprinkling water",
            "By curing compound application",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Ponding"
    },
    {
        "question": "Stiff concrete can be achieved by_______________.",
        "options": [
            "Low water/cement ratio",
            "High water/cement ratio",
            "Both",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Low water/cement ratio"
    },
    {
        "question": "Concrete can be transported by ________________.",
        "options": [
            "Truck Mixer",
            "By bucket",
            "With concrete pump",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a preliminary check before placing of concrete?",
        "options": [
            "Check for Curing",
            "Check for vibration",
            "Check for cover block",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Check for cover block"
    },
    {
    "question": "What are the benefits of seeking advice from seniors?",
    "options": [
        "It helps in error resolution",
        "It helps in completing the task early",
        "It helps in performing the task more effectively",
        "All of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above"
},
{
    "question": "Improper communication can lead to _____________.",
    "options": [
        "Completing work on time",
        "Hazardous conditions",
        "Delay in project completion",
        "All of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above"
},
{
    "question": "What are the main characteristics of a good work schedule?",
    "options": [
        "Priorities to important works",
        "Realistic timelines",
        "Both",
        "None of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Both"
},
{
    "question": "What would you do if there is short circuit in vacuum dewatering pump?",
    "options": [
        "Continue to work with it",
        "Throw away the pump",
        "Report it to the superiors",
        "None of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Report it to the superiors"
},
{
    "question": "What are the benefits of team discussion?",
    "options": [
        "It helps in delay of works",
        "It helps in bad quality of works",
        "It helps in improving work quality and understanding between the team",
        "None of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "It helps in improving work quality and understanding between the team"
},
{
    "question": "If there is a new technology used in a task that you donâ€™t know, what would you do in that situation?",
    "options": [
        "Do task with old technology",
        "Leave the task",
        "Seek advice from seniors",
        "None of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Seek advice from seniors"
},
{
    "question": "What would you do if you have a conflict with your teammate?",
    "options": [
        "Fight with him",
        "Abuse him",
        "Complain to the seniors",
        "Try to resolve the problems by talking to them"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Try to resolve the problems by talking to them"
},
{
    "question": "Which among the following is helpful in building good relationship between the various teams of the project?",
    "options": [
        "Interrupt them while working",
        "Ignore them",
        "Talk and discuss work with them",
        "None of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Talk and discuss work with them"
},
{
    "question": "What would you do if a member in your team is doing incorrect work?",
    "options": [
        "Fight with him",
        "Talk and show him the right way",
        "Complain to the seniors",
        "Ask him to stop the work and leave"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Talk and show him the right way"
},
{
    "question": "What happens when workers do not do the task as per the instructions?",
    "options": [
        "Works completes on time",
        "Work quality increases",
        "Delay in project and low quality",
        "None of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Delay in project and low quality"
},
{
    "question": "What would you do to complete a task in the given time frame?",
    "options": [
        "Show lazy behaviour",
        "Work alone",
        "Work with team by distributing work as per their competencies",
        "None of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Work with team by distributing work as per their competencies"
},
{
    "question": "What would you do if you have surplus material?",
    "options": [
        "Throw it away",
        "Waste it",
        "Keep it in a good place to avoid wastage",
        "None of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Keep it in a good place to avoid wastage"
},
{
    "question": "What are the demerits of bad housekeeping?",
    "options": [
        "It may cause tripping of worker",
        "It may cause unforeseen accidents",
        "It may lead to fire (Only for flammable material)",
        "All of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above"
},
{
    "question": "What would you decide to do first?",
    "options": [
        "Tasks which are not on priority",
        "Task which are on priority",
        "Both",
        "None of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Task which are on priority"
},
{
    "question": "How to avoid delay in consumption of concrete?",
    "options": [
        "Keep all the equipment ready for placement of concrete",
        "Keep all manpower attentive",
        "Keep initial preparation ready for placement",
        "All of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above"
},
{
    "question": "Why work schedules are important?",
    "options": [
        "It helps us in delaying a task",
        "It helps in delay of the project",
        "It helps in understanding the timelines and sequence of activities",
        "None of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "It helps in understanding the timelines and sequence of activities"
},
    {
    "question": "If you are assigned with a task to complete it in 5 hours, what will be your target?",
    "options": [
        "Complete the task within 5 hours",
        "You will not be bothered about time",
        "You will take your time to complete it",
        "None of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Complete the task within 5 hours"
},
{
    "question": "Will you tell your co-worker if he forgot to do an important work assigned to him?",
    "options": [
        "Fire him from the job",
        "Teach him the importance of resources",
        "Complain to seniors",
        "None of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Teach him the importance of resources"
},
{
    "question": "Which of the following is essential to understand the sequence of job?",
    "options": [
        "Job specification",
        "Method statement",
        "Progress tracker",
        "None of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Method statement"
},
{
    "question": "Which of the following is essential to understand the timeline of job?",
    "options": [
        "Work schedule",
        "Technical specification",
        "Work permit",
        "None of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Work schedule"
},
    {
    "question": "Which of the following is an unsafe working practice?",
    "options": [
        "Working on height with body harness",
        "Working on wet platform",
        "Working with hard hat on your head",
        "None of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Working on wet platform"
},
{
    "question": "Site safety induction is important, why?",
    "options": [
        "To aware the workers of safety practices",
        "To aware them of hazards and their resolutions",
        "To make them understand the importance of PPEâ€™s",
        "All of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above"
},
{
    "question": "What is the use of safety goggles?",
    "options": [
        "To protect ears from high pitched sound",
        "To protect the head from falling objects",
        "To protect eyes from dust and debris",
        "All of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "To protect eyes from dust and debris"
},
{
    "question": "Power tools should be operated by______________?",
    "options": [
        "A person with no expertise of that tool",
        "By masonâ€™s only",
        "By labours only",
        "A person with expertise in operation of that tool"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "A person with expertise in operation of that tool"
},
{
    "question": "Ladder should be placed at an angle of _________________ from ground.",
    "options": [
        "90Âº",
        "60Âº",
        "180Âº",
        "270Âº"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "60Âº"
},
    {
    "question": "It is required to store ______________ away from the electrical panels.",
    "options": [
        "Cement",
        "Sand",
        "Flammable material",
        "Bricks"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Flammable material"
},
{
    "question": "Which of the following is a good safety practice?",
    "options": [
        "Wearing PPEâ€™s on site",
        "Wearing body harness during working on height",
        "Wearing nose mask in dusty environment",
        "All of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above"
},
{
    "question": "What would you do after removal of shuttering?",
    "options": [
        "Throw away removed shuttering material",
        "Properly stage them away from walkway",
        "Let it remain on ground here and there",
        "All of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Properly stage them away from walkway"
}, {
        "question": "What structure is created to provide more accommodation within a restricted space?",
        "options": [
            "Plinth",
            "Floor",
            "Basement",
            "Superstructure"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Floor"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of floor is cheap, hard, and fairly impervious?",
        "options": [
            "Muram floor",
            "Mud floor",
            "Brick floor",
            "Flag stone floor"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Mud floor"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which floor uses cow-dung mixed with earth, and a thin layer of this mix is spread over the compacted layer?",
        "options": [
            "Mud floor",
            "Brick floor",
            "Muram floor",
            "Flag stone floor"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Mud floor"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are brick floors generally used?",
        "options": [
            "Residential building",
            "Educational building",
            "Assembly building",
            "Warehouses"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Warehouses"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which place is timber flooring most suitable for?",
        "options": [
            "Dancing hall",
            "Dining hall",
            "Community hall",
            "Prayer hall"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Dancing hall"
    },
    {
        "question": "What flooring is suitable for kitchens and toilets?",
        "options": [
            "Kota stone",
            "Terrazzo tiles",
            "Slate stone",
            "Brick floor"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Terrazzo tiles"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of flooring is suitable for lobby, reception, and main lounge?",
        "options": [
            "Ceramic tiles",
            "Marble floor",
            "Cement concrete tiles",
            "Agra red stone"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Ceramic tiles"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which floor is constructed below ground level?",
        "options": [
            "Ground floor",
            "First floor",
            "Sub-floor",
            "Basement floor"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Basement floor"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the thickness of the hard base concrete while constructing a marble floor?",
        "options": [
            "5 to 10 cm",
            "10 to 12 cm",
            "10 to 15 cm",
            "15 to 20 cm"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "10 to 15 cm"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of floor is mostly recommended to be used in courtyards, stores, godowns, etc.?",
        "options": [
            "Cement concrete floor",
            "Brick floor",
            "Tiled floor",
            "Muram floor"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Brick floor"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where tamping is done in compaction of concrete structure?",
        "options": [
            "Slab",
            "Foundation cement",
            "Column footing",
            "Underground floor"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Slab"
    },
    {
        "question": "What slab is designed for the ratio of the length and breadth is 2 or more?",
        "options": [
            "One way slab",
            "Two way slab",
            "Over hanging slab",
            "Cantilever slab"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "One way slab"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the dead load?",
        "options": [
            "Roof",
            "Snow",
            "Wind pressure",
            "Men and Animals"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Roof"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which method of site exploration is suitable for a depth of 6 to 8m range?",
        "options": [
            "Test pit",
            "Probing",
            "Auger boring",
            "Wash boring"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Auger boring"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the lowest part of building?",
        "options": [
            "Superstructure",
            "Wall",
            "Foundation",
            "Roof"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Foundation"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which part of a structure is in direct contact with the ground?",
        "options": [
            "Plinth",
            "Foundation",
            "Basement",
            "Superstructure"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Foundation"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which windows are provided for the only purpose of admitting light and vision in the room?",
        "options": [
            "Gable window",
            "Bay window",
            "Fixed window",
            "Sliding window"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Fixed window"
    },
    {
        "question": "What thumb rule is used to arrive at the width of a window?",
        "options": [
            "1/10 (Width of room + height of room)",
            "1/8 (Width of room + height of room)",
            "1/6 (Width of room + height of room)",
            "1/4 (Width of room + height of room)"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "1/8 (Width of room + height of room)"
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of hinges are used where the shutters are thin?",
        "options": [
            "Butt hinge",
            "Back flap hinge",
            "Garnet hinge",
            "Strap hinge"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Back flap hinge"
    },
    {
        "question": "What holes allow any moisture that penetrates in the wall to flow outside?",
        "options": [
            "Top holes",
            "Bottom holes",
            "Center holes",
            "Weep holes"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Weep holes"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which pattern is suitable for sloping hills in refuse collection?",
        "options": [
            "Fan pattern",
            "Interceptor pattern",
            "Radial pattern",
            "Zonal pattern"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Zonal pattern"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which refuse collection system, having automatic flushing, is provided by water?",
        "options": [
            "Separate system of sewerage",
            "Combined system of sewerage",
            "Partially combined system of sewerage",
            "Partially separated system of sewerage"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Combined system of sewerage"
    },
    {
        "question": "Name the sloped roof that is formed with one slope only.",
        "options": [
            "Lean-to-roof",
            "Couple roof",
            "Couple-close roof",
            "Collar roof"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Lean-to-roof"
    },
   
    {
        "question": "What is the maximum span of close couple roof?",
        "options": [
            "2.4 m",
            "3.6 m",
            "4.2 m",
            "4.8 m"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "4.2 m"
    }





    
]
